Akane, I'm sorry…
茜，抱歉
I've…
我…
found someone else.
喜歡上其他女生了
Well…
難怪…
I did think he was acting distant, lately.
我就覺得他最近變冷淡了
ORIGINAL STORY BY MASHIRO
（原作：Mashiro）
A girl from an online game stole your boyfriend?!
男友被線上遊戲的女網友搶走了？
Seriously? That's hilarious!
感覺好有趣，怎麼回事？
Momo, not so loud…
小桃，你太大聲了
When you say game,
你說的遊戲
you mean the PC game you were playing together, right?
是你們一起在電腦上玩的那個吧？
That's the one.
是啊
I never knew that sort of thing happened in video games.
原來玩遊戲還會遇到這種事
Akane!
茜
Why don't you play this game too?
你也一起來玩這遊戲吧
Huh? What is it?
這是什麼？
It's the newest online game.
是新的線上遊戲
I did worry he was too much of a gamer,
雖然我的確覺得他是個電玩迷
but I never thought gaming would lead him to cheat on me.
沒想到他會劈腿遊戲的女網友
Worse, this was the last text he sent me.
而且他最後傳的訊息還是這個
Yikes, that stings.
爛透了
No words for that one.
真的讓人無言以對
You're better off without him.
分手是正確的吧
It might hurt now, but…
雖然你現在還是會難過啦
I have a lecture this afternoon. Gotta go.
我下午有課，先走囉
Don't stay down in the dumps forever
你也不要一蹶不振
and make sure you come to class.
記得來上課哦
Being a hermit will only make things worse.
關在家裡只會更難過哦
I know…
也是啦
Getting dumped doesn't mean I'm gonna die.
只是被甩又不會死
Daily life goes on
日子還是要過
and I can't afford to skip class.
大學也不能一直翹課
I'd like a part-time job too.
也差不多想去打工了
I wonder if he actually retrieved the armor.
他有好好回收裝備了嗎？
MAINTENANCE NOTIFICATION
（遊戲維修通知）
I never had any interest in games…
我原本對電玩沒有興趣
but if we could enjoy it together,
但只要兩人一起玩得開心
I was happy to play along.
我就滿足了
SELECT CHARACTER: AKANE, PALADIN
（角色選擇，職業：聖騎士 鐵鎚、鐵盾，啟程之服）
He even deleted me from his friends list.
他還記得刪我好友
He doesn't miss a beat.
分得真是清楚
More importantly…
話說回來
If I knew we were gonna break up, I could've saved money.
知道會分手，我就不在遊戲花錢了
I spent 3,000 yen on my in-game costume.
我花了三千買遊戲裝扮耶
All I'm left with is this waste of a character I built up.
只剩下白費時間培養的角色
Strike!
攻擊…
Power…
集氣…
Excuse me…
那個…
Huh?
奇怪？
Who's this stone-faced guy with the afro?
這個冷面爆炸頭是誰？
He looks kind of familiar.
我好像在哪裡看過
His name is…
是同一個公會的成員
Yamada.
山田…
AKANE: GOOD MORNING, YAMADA-KUN
（山田，早啊）
YAMADA: HI
（你好）
AKANE: ARE YOU HUNTING TOO?
（你也在狩獵嗎？）
YAMADA: YEAH
（對）
I remember him now.
他的確是這樣的人
He's so expressionless, it left a bad impression on me.
總是很冷淡，對他沒有好印象
And why did it take him two minutes
話說只是回“你好”和“對”
just to type "hi" and "yeah."
為什麼要花兩分鐘啊？
YAMADA: YOU'RE NOT AIMING FOR THE PROPHET'S STONE, ARE YOU?
（你難道是在刷預言者之石嗎？）
AKANE: WHAT'S THAT?
（那是什麼？）
YAMADA: IT'S A RARE ITEM LEFT BY 0.1% OF EVERY 22 MOBS
（這裡的雜怪 有0.01%機率會掉的寶）
He seems like one of those addict types too.
而且還是很沉迷的類型
"No, not that."
趕快否認一下
No, not that.
我沒在刷啦
My boyfriend dumped me yesterday,
只是不爽昨天被男友甩
so I was taking out my frustration.
隨便狩獵一下
Oh, and get this!
聽我說一下啦
He was cheating on me because of this game.
他竟然是因為這遊戲劈腿
What a jerk!
真是爛透了
TWO MINUTES LATER
（兩分鐘後）
Oh, is that so?
哦，是哦
IF YOU'RE NOT LOOKING FOR RARE ITEMS,
（既然你沒在刷寶）
CAN YOU LET ME USE THE HUNTING GROUND?
（能把這個狩獵場讓給我嗎？）
Zero desire to converse with me, huh?
表示他完全不想跟我說話吧
Absolutely not!
絕對不要
I found this hunting ground first,
是我先來這個狩獵場的
so the proper thing is to refrain until I'm finished.
晚到的你應該要自己退讓
I was told that's proper hunting-ground etiquette.
我聽說這才是狩獵場的禮貌
I'm sure you're uninterested,
雖然你八成沒興趣
but I'm suffering from a broken heart.
我現在因為失戀，傷心得很
This hunting ground shall be my stress reliever.
我要在這個狩獵場大肆發洩
Please look for the Prophet's Stone on another channel.
請你去其他頻道刷預言者之石
I shall not permit anyone else to use this space!
我絕對不會讓出這個地方
Oh no!
糟糕
I lost my cool
我不小心太火大
and took out my frustration on an afro-haired stranger.
對陌生人的爆炸頭亂發脾氣
Well, I guess…
也是啦
you're right…
我的確…
I CAN'T SAY I'M INTERESTED.
（是沒興趣啦）
I hate you, Yamada!
我討厭山田！
I'm gonna stay online until you leave!
我要故意等山田離開後再登出
This is why I hate gamer guys!
所以我才討厭電玩迷的男生啦！
ONE-YEAR ANNIVERSARY EVENT
（決定舉辦一周年活動）
An event?
活動？
Attendees will receive avatars or other special prizes.
參加者可獲得造型和各種贈品…
The location is nearby.
就在這附近嘛
Akane!
茜
Let's stay together, forever!
我們要永遠在一起哦
Right!
嗯
Sorry…
抱歉
While playing that game, I…
我在那個遊戲裡…
fell in love with someone else.
喜歡上其他女生了
They said they're in love with me too.
對方也說她喜歡我
I'm really sorry.
真的很抱歉
I'm sure…
反正他已經…
he's already dating her.
和那個女生在一起了吧
Does that mean…
不曉得他們…
they'll go to the event, together?
會不會一起去這個活動？
Damn it!
可惡
He can't just dump me and get away unscathed!
誰甘心就這樣被甩掉啊？
Akane!
茜
You finally came to class!
你終於來學校了啊
Over it, already?
已經振作起來了嗎？
Momo…
小桃
Hey, Momo…
欸，小桃
Help me shop for a new outfit and shoes today.
今天陪我去買衣服和鞋子
Are you going somewhere?
你是要去哪裡嗎？
Yeah, I decided to attend an event.
嗯，我決定要去參加一場活動
And at that event,
那場活動
that creep will be there too.
我猜他八成也會來
Let him cry bitter tears when he sees how beautiful I've become.
我要讓他看見變美的我，深深後悔
You're not over it at all!
根本沒有振作嘛
Please tell me it's not an event for that online game.
應該不是那個遊戲的活動吧？
No can do!
哪有什麼“應該”？
Of course it's for that game.
當然是那個遊戲的活動啊
There's a high chance he'll be there.
他有很高的機率會出現
That's pretty cringe.
好悲情
Say what you like.
隨便你怎麼說
Incredible…
真強
-He'll rue the day. -Please make me look cute!
-請讓我變可愛！ -竟然甩了我，選擇遊戲的女網友
-That he ever left me. -Please make me look thin!
-請讓我變纖細 -我一定要讓他後悔
-For that gaming tramp. -Of course!
-好的 -絕對要讓他
I'll make him regret it!
懊悔自己的遺憾決定
Thank you for attending today's Forest of Savior Autumn Event!
今天謝謝大家來參加FOS秋季慶典
The PIN number you received at the entrance
入場時發放的PIN碼
is valid until the end of December.
有效期限到12月底
This is a pretty big event…
-沒想到辦得這麼盛大耶 -大家要注意哦
There are way more people than I expected.
人比想像中的還要多
Huh?
奇怪？
Wait a minute…
這麼說起來
Did I just blow my entire monthly budget?
我這個月確定要吃土了？
In any case,
話說回來
everyone here is playing the same online game, huh?
這裡所有人都在玩同一個遊戲吧
There sure are a lot of guys.
總覺得男生特別多
It's pretty mysterious…
感覺真是奇妙
I wonder what their characters are like?
不曉得大家是用什麼角色
Takuma!
拓馬
Taku…ma…?
拓…馬…
-Ta-- -Let's get closer to the stage.
-拓… -我們去前面一點吧
Sure.
好
W… wait!
等…等等！
What happened?
怎麼了？
That hurt!
好痛…
That girl tripped.
有女生跌倒了
I'm such a moron.
我真蠢
I wish I could disappear.
好想消失
At this rate…
總覺得…
I'm gonna cry!
突然變得好想哭
Are you okay?
你沒事吧？
Whoa, a hottie!
超級大帥哥
Yes! I'm fine!
是的，沒事
Did I bump into you, by any chance?
難不成我撞到你了嗎？
Yes.
是的
I'm so sorry! I was drifting off, or better put,
抱歉，我有點心不在焉
I had something on my mind, and…
或者該說是在想事情吧
I'm going through a rough patch
我遇到一些難過的事
and I've lost sight of what's around me.
不小心沒注意到周圍…
Oh.
是哦
That so?
這樣啊
Sorry. You don't care, do you?
抱歉，和你無關吧
Um…
對
Well…
這個嘛…
I can't say I'm interested.
我是沒興趣啦
Huh? That line…
奇怪？這句話…
I've heard it somewhere, recently.
最近好像在哪裡聽過
I CAN'T SAY I'M INTERESTED.
（我是沒興趣啦）
Yamada?
山田？
Yamada with the afro?
爆炸頭山田？
Who are you?
你是誰？
Um…
那個…
I, uh…
就是…
Huh?
奇怪？
Not much of a reaction.
他的反應好遲鈍
But then, I'm sure I felt déjà vu.
雖然他講話的確很像那個爆炸頭
Is it my imagination?
但應該是錯覺吧
Is it too big of a coincidence?
才沒有那麼巧吧
Uh-oh, he's looking at me with really creeped-out eyes now.
話說他露出超質疑的眼神在看我
Is he the wrong guy?!
果然是認錯人了
Please forgive me…
不好意思…
Takuma… and his new girlfriend?
拓馬…和新女友
What are you doing here?
你為什麼在這裡？
Oh, Takuma! What a coincidence!
拓馬，真的好巧哦
You're Yamada, aren't you?!
-這不是山田嗎？ -什麼？
You're Yamada, right?
你是山田吧？
Who's he?
誰啊？
Don't you know?
你不曉得嗎？
He's a super-famous pro gamer.
他是超有名的職業玩家哦
Wow!
好強
Wow is right!
他真的超強的
Does this mean you play FOS, Mr. Yamada?
山田有在玩FOS嗎？
I'm a huge fan of yours!
我是你的粉絲
I watch all your videos.
我都有在看你的影片
This is such a thrill!
太感動了
Oh, man!
超酷！
You're famous?
你是名人嗎？
Well, in small circles.
算吧，僅限某個領域
Fancy that, Takuma!
真巧耶，拓馬
Are you on a date too?
你們也在約會嗎？
Oh, it's Akane.
這不是茜嗎？
You're here too?
你在哦？
I've been here the whole time!
我一直都在啊
What are you doing at a place like this?
你在這裡做什麼啊？
I play the game too.
我也有在玩那個遊戲
Is it so surprising that I'm here?
來這裡不奇怪吧
Don't tell me you came alone?
難道你一個人跑來？
Of course not.
怎麼可能？
Let me introduce you
我來介紹一下
to my new boyfriend!
這是我的新男友
Not true.
並不是
Please…
求求你了
Take pity on this lowly peasant and play along.
就當作幫助弱小，配合我演戲吧
Are you crazy?
你認真的嗎？
Consider it an act of charity.
請你當成舉手之勞，幫幫我吧
I'll give you this.
這個給你
I got it as a present for attending.
這是我拿到的參加者贈品
If you like…
請你收下
Seriously?
真的假的？
That's the PIN code for the Prophet's Stone.
這是預言者之石的PIN碼哦
It's an extremely rare power-up stone.
是超稀有的強化石哦
It is?
原來是這樣啊
I'm her boyfriend.
我是她男友
He's my boyfriend!
他是我男友
Y… you can't be serious.
不會吧？
I've been following him for three years
我追蹤他的帳號三年
and haven't even gotten one response.
從來沒有收到回覆過…
DESPITE COMMENTING ON ALL HIS POSTS…
（我每次都有留言的說…）
I'm humiliated!
真不甘心！
Takuma!
拓馬！
-So humiliated… -I win!
-不甘心… -我贏了！
It's not what I imagined, but…
雖然跟我設想的不太一樣
-He's humiliated. -So humiliated…
-不甘心… -但他確實在懊悔
Takuma, cheer up!
拓馬，打起精神來
Eri!
繪里
Takuma!
拓馬
IZAKAYA BOTTA
（博大居酒屋）
Welcome!
歡迎光臨
How can I put it…?
該怎麼說…
This feeling…
這種心情是怎麼回事？
It's like I won the battle but lost the war.
好像贏了面子，卻輸了裡子
Can you really say you won the battle?
你連面子也沒贏吧
From what I saw…
看上去是這樣
You're definitely Yamada with the afro.
你果然是爆炸頭山田吧
Well… By the way, can I go?
對，話說我可以回去了嗎？
He's definitely Yamada.
果然是山田
Come on! Just keep me company!
有什麼關係，就陪我嘛
I don't wanna be alone right now!
人家不想一個人獨處
That girl…
那個女生…
She was really pretty.
長得好漂亮
Who was?
你說誰？
Takuma's girlfriend.
就是拓馬的女友
For starters, who's Takuma?
我連拓馬是誰也不知道
My ex-boyfriend!
我的前男友啦
I told you everything in the game chat!
我在遊戲聊天室說過了吧！
You're that wimpy looking paladin?
大姐你是那個打很爛的聖騎士啊
You only figured it out now?
你現在才發現嗎？
It's impressive that I figured it out at all.
光是能發現就很厲害了吧？
Welcome!
歡迎光臨
In truth, today…
今天原本…
I wanted him to see me dolled up
是想展現打扮時髦的我
and make him regret dumping me.
讓他後悔甩了我
I never wanted
我根本…
to see them together like that.
不想看到那樣的場面
Um…
那個…
This could take a while.
看來好像會沒完沒了
Can I refill my cola?
我可以再點一杯可樂嗎？
As much as you want.
隨你的便
Our pleasure!
-樂意之至！
I'm feeling less tense, somehow.
感覺突然沒力了
That reminds me, what's a pro gamer?
話說剛才拓馬也有提到
Takuma mentioned it…
職業玩家是什麼？
I suppose it's anyone who gets money from a sponsor for playing a game.
靠玩遊戲從贊助商那邊收錢的人吧
A sponsor?
贊助商？
No way!
不會吧？
It's true.
是真的
Do you get paid to play FOS too?
所以你是拿錢在玩FOS嗎？
That's just for relaxation.
那只是我休閒玩的
I mainly play FPS.
我主要是玩FPS
What's that?
那是什麼？
Uh, never mind.
當我沒說
FPS MEANS FIRST-PERSON SHOOTER
（First-person shooter簡稱為FPS）
Aren't you being a bit cold?
你會不會太冷淡了啊？
You won't get many girls that way.
這樣沒有女人緣吧
I don't.
我是沒女人緣
I've never had a girlfriend.
也沒交過女友
You can't be serious.
不會吧？
Didn't you just say I won't get girls?
剛才是大姐你說我沒女人緣吧？
Yeah, I did, but…
是這樣沒錯啦
A hot guy like you must have girls crawling over him.
你長這麼帥，不可能沒女人緣吧
IS THIS MODESTY?!
（謙虛什麼啦！）
I can't say I'm interested.
我沒興趣啊
I don't get romance and all that.
談戀愛什麼的，我也搞不懂
What a waste of a hot guy.
真是浪費一張帥臉
I have more fun gaming.
玩遊戲開心多了
SUCH A WASTE…
（太浪費了…）
Well, romance isn't all wine and roses, anyway.
反正談戀愛也不全是開心的事
Some people get cheated on through a video game, like me.
可能會像我這樣因為遊戲被劈腿
Sounds miserable.
真悽慘耶
Miserable…
悽慘啊…
Oh no, here come the tears.
糟糕，我開始想哭了
I need to use the restroom.
我去一下洗手間
My clothes are a mess.
衣服髒掉了
I must have dirtied them when I fell.
是摔倒的時候弄髒的吧
Ow…!
好痛…
I scraped my foot too.
腳也有擦傷
IT'S BLEEDING…
（流血了…）
I never should have gone to such a stupid event.
早知道就不去那種活動了
Not if it makes me feel like this.
這樣就不會難受了
Huh?
奇怪？
He…
那傢伙…
Don't tell me he went home?
該不會回去了吧？
Well, it figures.
非常有可能
He looked like he could bolt at any moment.
他一副很想回去的樣子
LET ME OUTTA HERE!
（好想回去）
Not that it matters…
其實也沒差啦
I was forcing him to keep me company, after all.
本來就是我硬拖他來的
I guess
反正…
I'd better get used to being alone.
今後我也是孤單一人
Are you okay?
你沒事吧？
What's with that face?
你那是什麼臉？
Y…Yama… Ya… Maya…
山…田…
Anyway, mind sitting down?
總之你可以先坐下來嗎？
What's that?
那是什麼？
A bandage.
OK繃
I went out for about ten seconds to buy one.
我剛才用10秒左右買回來的
Crap, it's stuck.
糟糕，黏住了
I'm gonna put it on now.
我就直接貼上去了
You went to buy that for me?
你幫我買來的嗎？
The blood was hard to ignore.
因為我看你在流血，覺得很在意
And so you took the time?
所以特地去買嗎？
I guess.
算是啦
I had about three colas too.
而且我也喝了三杯可樂
Yamada!
山田
IZAKAYA BOTTA
（博大居酒屋）
Keep ordering whatever you like!
你再盡情地點吧
No, it's about time I--
不，我差不多…
We're getting drunk tonight!
今晚要不醉不歸！
Wait, um…
那個…
I'd like to make an order, please!
我們要點餐！
Our pleasure!
樂意之至！
Anyway, Tani's watching the perimeter.
谷哥會幫忙注意周圍
We can concentrate on the frontlines.
我們能集中精神在前面
We might wrack up a lot of kills.
或許可以趁機多殺一點
My head is killing me…
頭好痛…
Especially on the next map.
特別是下張地圖…
And why do I keep hearing someone's voice?
從剛才就聽到有人在說話…
I told you, I'm not turning the camera on.
我就說不開鏡頭了
Who's there?
是誰？
Quit pestering me.
你很煩耶
Sorry, I have to step away.
抱歉，我離開一下
I'll be right back.
馬上回來
VERY PIGTAILEY, YAMATO NADESICO, SAMURAI, TWISTY PONYTAIL
（誇張雙馬尾 大和撫子2 武士頭 麻花辮馬尾）
Yup, there are no cute free haircuts.
果然免費的髮型都不可愛
Then again, all the cute ones are Gacha.
但是可愛的都要用抽的
WILD FLOWERS GACHA MOONLIT NIGHT GACHA
（從花園扭蛋中獲得 夢幻花少女）
I'll never win one of those.
反正一定抽不到
EDGE OF THE LAKE GACHA STARRY TOWER GACHA
（從月夜扭蛋中獲得 妖精雙馬尾）
Some of them are discounted.
也有定額商品啊？
They're not as good as the Gacha,
雖然沒花錢抽的好看
but they're cuter than the default.
但至少比預設造型可愛
SHORT WITH BUN, VIRGIN TWIN-TAILS, CURLY GIRL, SEAWEED HELMET
（新手推薦）
I see…
原來如此
Get the discounted ones
像這樣花一點小錢
to add some individuality on a budget.
也可以打造出特色
I bought the cutest discount style they had!
買下定額商品裡最可愛的了
We all had the same idea.
大家想的都一樣